Guide to the Art and Architecture Library, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Art and Architecture Library, Yale University, records
1873-2000
RU 470
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
(2 boxes)
The records consist of accession books, acquisition books, account books, and inventories documenting the operations of the Yale Art & Architecture Library.
Yale University. Art & Architecture Library
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of accession books, acquisition books, account books, and inventories documenting the operations of the Yale Art & Architecture Library.
Academic libraries -- Departmental libraries; Architectural libraries; Art libraries; Yale University. Art & Architecture Library
- Records, 1873-1978; Accession 1981-A-055
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - 7 vols of accession books, 1873-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1 account book, 1934-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 2 account books of acquisition totals, 1972-1978? (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1 acquisition account book, 1961-69 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 20 pp. of loose inventory records, 1948-1958? (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Administrative records, 1924-2000; Accession 2003-A-002
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
  - Annual reports
    - Art and Architecture Library
      - 1924-1933 (Box 1)
      - 1933-1943 (Box 1)
      - 1943-1953 (Box 1)
      - 1953-1963 (Box 1)
      - 1963-1973 (Box 1)
      - 1973-1983 (Box 1)
      - 1983-1991 (Box 1)
      - 1994-2000 (Box 1)
    - Arts of the Book Collection, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
    - Classics Library, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
    - Drama Library, 1995-2000 (Box 1)
    - Visual Resources Collection, 1996-2000 (Box 1)
  - Library business
    - Art and Architecture Library Committee meeting minutes, agendas, correspondence, 1948-1957 (Box 1)
    - Art and Architecture Library Committee meeting minutes, agendas, correspondence, 1958-1991 (Box 1)
    - Library history narratives, Undated (Box 1)
    - Library reclassing project, 1948-1952 (Box 1)
    - miscellaneous -preservation notes; symposium, 1957-1970 (Box 1)
    - staffing issues, Undated (Box 1)
  - Plant issues
    - asbestos abatement, 1971-1975 (Box 1)
    - Committee on Art and Architecture Building Problems -minutes and agendas, 1974 (Box 1)
    - exterior renovation, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - general, 1967-1973 (Box 1)
    - general, 1974-1988 (Box 1)
    - general, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
    - Repairs and Maintenance Requirements for the Art and Architecture Building, Yale University. Report, 1987 January 5 (Box 1)
  - Space planning
    - general, 1958-1979 (Box 1)
    - general, 1980-1995 (Box 1)
    - York/Chapel Planning Study, 1990 March (Box 1)